{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
              "A. 14th",
              "B. 15th",
              "C. 16th",
              "D. 17th"
            ],
            "question": "Sarbananda Sonowal is the _______ Chief Minister of Assam",
            "answer": "A. 14th"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jamuna",
              "B. Padma",
              "C. Meghna",
              "D. Dihang"
            ],
            "question": "Brahmaputra, after joining Tista river, is known as",
            "answer": "A. Jamuna"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kamrup",
              "B. Nagaon",
              "C. Jorhat",
              "D. Dibrugarh"
            ],
            "question": "The first Book Fair in Assam was held at",
            "answer": "B. Nagaon"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Pramatta Singha",
              "B. Rudra Singha",
              "C. Siva Singha",
              "D. Rajeswar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The book \"Hastividyarnava\" was written under which Ahom ruler",
            "answer": "C. Siva Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Tangla",
              "B. Hajo",
              "C. Sarthebari",
              "D. Sualkuchi"
            ],
            "question": "Which place is well known for its bell metal craft",
            "answer": "C. Sarthebari"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Prithibir Akukh",
              "B. Golam",
              "C. Koka Deutar har",
              "D. Aghari Atmar Kahini"
            ],
            "question": "Syed Abdul Malik won the Sahitya Akademi Award in 1972 for which one novel",
            "answer": "D. Aghari Atmar Kahini"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Rudra Baruah",
              "B. Parvati Prasad Baruwa",
              "C. Bishnuprasad Rabha",
              "D. Jyoti Prasad Agarwala"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as the Luit Konwar of Assam",
            "answer": "A. Rudra Baruah"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jayanta Madhab Bora",
              "B. Leena Sarma",
              "C. Sailen Bharali",
              "D. Lakshminandan Bora"
            ],
            "question": "Who won the Sahitya Akademi Award 2017 in Assamese Language",
            "answer": "A. Jayanta Madhab Bora"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Adaram Basumatary",
              "B. Durgeswar Boro",
              "C. Rabiram Ramchiary",
              "D. Rita Boro"
            ],
            "question": "Who won the Sahitya Akademi Award 2017 in Bodo Language",
            "answer": "D. Rita Boro"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. FIFA U-17 World Cup",
              "B. National Games",
              "C. AIBA Women's Youth World Championship",
              "D. South Asian (SAARC) Badminton Championship"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following sports event is not hosted in Guwahati in the year 2017",
            "answer": "B. National Games"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 56 Kg",
              "B. 60 Kg",
              "C. 64 Kg",
              "D. 68 Kg"
            ],
            "question": "In which Kg category of Boxing, Ankushita Boro wins the Gold medal in AIBA World Youth Championship",
            "answer": "C. 64 Kg"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 15th July, 1935",
              "B. 7th April, 1937",
              "C. 12th May, 1939",
              "D. 15th June, 1940"
            ],
            "question": "The first session of the Assam Assembly was held in",
            "answer": "B. 7th April, 1937"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Babu Basanta Kumar Das",
              "B. Debeswar Sarmah",
              "C. Laksheswar Borooah",
              "D. Kuladhar Chaliha"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first Speaker of the Assam Assembly",
            "answer": "A. Babu Basanta Kumar Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bakata",
              "B. Garhgaon",
              "C. Charaideo",
              "D. Jorhat"
            ],
            "question": "Which one Ahom Kingdom's capital was located by the Dihing river",
            "answer": "A. Bakata"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1904",
              "B. 1908",
              "C. 1911",
              "D. 1915"
            ],
            "question": "Tocklai Tea Research Institute which is world's oldest and largest tea research institute, was established in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1911"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1950",
              "B. 1952",
              "C. 1955",
              "D. 1958"
            ],
            "question": "Bordoloi Trophy was first started in the year",
            "answer": "B. 1952"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Gauhati Town Club",
              "B. Assam Police AC",
              "C. East Bengal Club",
              "D. Mohun Bagan AC"
            ],
            "question": "Which team wins the Bordoloi Trophy football tournament for most of the numbers",
            "answer": "D. Mohun Bagan AC"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Shiva Thapa",
              "B. Bhogeswar Baruah",
              "C. Dipankar Bhattacharjee",
              "D. Jayanta Talukdar"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the first olympian from Assam to participate in olympic games",
            "answer": "C. Dipankar Bhattacharjee"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. US",
              "B. UK",
              "C. Canada",
              "D. South Africa"
            ],
            "question": "Elvis Ali Hazarika become first swimmer from the Northeast to cross the Catalina Channel which is located at",
            "answer": "A. US"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 2004",
              "B. 2005",
              "C. 2006",
              "D. 2007"
            ],
            "question": "Jayanta Talukdar has won individual gold Medal in the Archery World Cup in the year",
            "answer": "C. 2006"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Amalprava Das",
              "B. Nalini Bala Devi",
              "C. Chandra Prava Saikiani",
              "D. Malati Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the first women from Assam to received the Padma Sri Award",
            "answer": "A. Amalprava Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Krishna Kanta Handique",
              "B. Navakanta Barua",
              "C. Benudhar Sharma",
              "D. Omeo Kumar Das"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the first person from Assam to received the Padma Bhushan award",
            "answer": "D. Omeo Kumar Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Krishna Kanta Handique",
              "B. Surya Kumar Bhuyan",
              "C. Amalprava Das",
              "D. Omeo Kumar Das"
            ],
            "question": "Who had declined to accept India's second highest civilian award Padma Vibhushan",
            "answer": "C. Amalprava Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 5",
              "B. 7",
              "C. 8",
              "D. 10"
            ],
            "question": "How many maximum members are elected from Assam for Rajya Sabha",
            "answer": "B. 7"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 2",
              "B. 3",
              "C. 4",
              "D. 6"
            ],
            "question": "How many members were elected for the first rajya Sabha session of 1952 from Assam",
            "answer": "A. 2"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Indira P. P. Bora",
              "B. Jogendra Nath Phukan",
              "C. Joyshree Goswami Mahanta",
              "D. Lakshmi Nandan Bora"
            ],
            "question": "Who had received Padma Shri Award in the Art category from Assam in the year 2020",
            "answer": "A. Indira P. P. Bora"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Gopinath Bordoloi",
              "B. Tarun Ram Phukan",
              "C. Bishnuram Medhi",
              "D. Bimala Prasad Chaliha"
            ],
            "question": "Which politician is also known as \"Iron man of Assam\"",
            "answer": "C. Bishnuram Medhi"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Gadadhar Singha",
              "B. Rudra Singha",
              "C. Siva Singha",
              "D. Pramatta Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king raising a vast composite army with the aim to attack Bengal of the Mughal Empire",
            "answer": "B. Rudra Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bhutivarman",
              "B. Pushyavarman",
              "C. Samudravarman",
              "D. Bhaskaravarman"
            ],
            "question": "Which of the following King of the Varman dynasty perform Ashvamedha Yagnya",
            "answer": "A. Bhutivarman"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Sutuphaa",
              "B. Sujangphaa",
              "C. Suhenphaa",
              "D. Suklenmung"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king was killed during the conflict with Chutia Kingdom",
            "answer": "A. Sutuphaa"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Varman kingdom",
              "B. Ahom kingdom",
              "C. Chutia kingdom",
              "D. Kamata kingdom"
            ],
            "question": "According to historians, the rise of which kingdom marked the end of the ancient period and the beginning of themedieval period in the history of Assam",
            "answer": "D. Kamata kingdom"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1951",
              "B. 1958",
              "C. 1960",
              "D. 1963"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Official Language Act was passed in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1960"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Nalini Bala Devi",
              "B. Syed Abdul Malik",
              "C. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
              "D. Ambikagiri Raichoudhury"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the founder of \"Axom Jaatiyo Mohaaxobhaa\"",
            "answer": "D. Ambikagiri Raichoudhury"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Hema Saraswati",
              "B. Madhava Kandali",
              "C. Madhavadeva",
              "D. Mahim Bora"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese poet is also known as \"Kaviraja\"",
            "answer": "B. Madhava Kandali"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Telugu",
              "B. Kannada",
              "C. Tamil",
              "D. Bengali"
            ],
            "question": "Madhava Kandali's \"Saptakanda Ramayana\" is considered to be the second translation from the Sanskrit into a modernregional language. Which one was the first language",
            "answer": "C. Tamil"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Assam Mihir",
              "B. Asam Darpan",
              "C. Chandrodaya",
              "D. Asam Dipak"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the first newspaper published in Guwahati",
            "answer": "A. Assam Mihir"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1885",
              "B. 1891",
              "C. 1895",
              "D. 1897"
            ],
            "question": "The first English weekly of Assam \"The Times of Assam\" was printed in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1895"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Nabakanta Barua",
              "B. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
              "C. Syed Abdul Malik",
              "D. Rajanikanta Bordoloi"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as the Walter Scott of Assamese literature",
            "answer": "D. Rajanikanta Bordoloi"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bijuli",
              "B. Orunodoi",
              "C. Jonaki",
              "D. Roopkar"
            ],
            "question": "First Assamese novel \"Bhanumati\" was first published in which magazine",
            "answer": "A. Bijuli"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jorhat",
              "B. Tezpur",
              "C. Mangaldoi",
              "D. Hajo"
            ],
            "question": "The ancient Mahabhairav Temple is located in which city",
            "answer": "B. Tezpur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dibrugarh",
              "B. Digboi",
              "C. Tinsukia",
              "D. Jorhat"
            ],
            "question": "First metre gauge line in Assam was setup between _____ to Margherita",
            "answer": "A. Dibrugarh"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Diphu",
              "B. Sivasagar",
              "C. Jorhat",
              "D. Karimganj"
            ],
            "question": "Which one city is being awarded 1st place in the “Cleanest City (Population between 50,000-1,00,000) North-EastZone\" category in Swachh Survekshan 2020",
            "answer": "C. Jorhat"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Guwahati",
              "B. Jorhat",
              "C. Sivsagar",
              "D. Nagaon"
            ],
            "question": "The National Institute Of Design is located in which city",
            "answer": "B. Jorhat"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1765",
              "B. 1770",
              "C. 1783",
              "D. 1788"
            ],
            "question": "Sivasagar was the capital of the Ahom Kingdom from 1699 to ______",
            "answer": "D. 1788"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dibrugarh",
              "B. Majuli",
              "C. Kaliabor",
              "D. Rangapara"
            ],
            "question": "Assam Chief Minister Sarbananda Sonowal represents which constituencies in the Assam Legislative Assembly",
            "answer": "B. Majuli"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1955",
              "B. 1957",
              "C. 1959",
              "D. 1962"
            ],
            "question": "Assam State Zoo cum Botanical Garden was established in",
            "answer": "B. 1957"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 32",
              "B. 36",
              "C. 38",
              "D. 42"
            ],
            "question": "Types of Bamboo species found in Assam is",
            "answer": "D. 42"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Manas",
              "B. Nameri",
              "C. Orang",
              "D. Kaziranga"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is not a Tiger Reserves of Assam",
            "answer": "C. Orang"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Chandubi Lake",
              "B. Rudrasagar Lake",
              "C. Jeypore Rainforest",
              "D. Deepar Beel"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is a only Ramsar site in Assam",
            "answer": "D. Deepar Beel"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 4",
              "B. 5",
              "C. 6",
              "D. 7"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of Elephant Reserves in Assam is",
            "answer": "B. 5"
          }
    ]
}